## Firmware Engineer

## **Carlos Silva**

Electrical Engineer major in Electronics with extensive experience in firmware development and embedded systems. My programming expertise lies in languages such as C, C++, and C#. In addition to my background as a developer in these languages,. I have knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, and Web API, and I have gained substantial experience with libraries and frameworks including React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and Styled Components.

I am a self-motivated and dedicated professional who is proficient at working both collaboratively and independently.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **The Factory HKA,** Caracas (Remote) — *Firmware Engineer*

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

Firmware development for embedded systems used in tax solutions; tax printers, and transmission devices using C/C++, React, Web API.

Firmware migration to other architectures due to microcontroller scarcity using C/C++.

Desktop application development to update firmware on tax printers or transmission devices using C#.

# **Freelance,** Lima (Remote) — *Embedded System & Frontend Developer*

NOVEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Firmware development for embedded systems C/C++.

Firmware update, code optimization, and application of best practices based on MISRA and CERT C.

Dashboard development for data visualization in IoT systems React, Web API, MQTT.

Development of a smart traffic light management application based on Electron JS, React, and DevExtreme library. State management using Redux.

Creation of multiple websites using WordPress, Gatsby, and Next.js.

Email templates for email marketing campaigns.

Collaboration in the development of an employee and payroll management application based on SQL Server, C#, .NET Framework, Web API, MVC, and ¡Query.

#### **Genialprojects,** Lima (Remote) — *Firmware Engineer*

NOVEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2018

Firmware development of a thermometer for temperature tracking and fever detection. An app for Android and iOS allows tracking of temperature, fever status and battery level. Historical data can be accessed and monitored through the Internet. The firmware can be updated over the air.

### Lima, Perú +51 942-314-138

clsilva@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/carloslsilva

#### **SKILLS**

C, C++, C# HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Web API React, Next.js, Node.js Tailwind CSS, Styled Components GIT

#### **SOFTWARE**

Linux (Debian derivatives)

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Basic)
Spanish (Native)

## **The Factory HKA,** Caracas — Firmware Engineer

MAY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016

Firmware and management application development for a keyboard (SmartKey) designed to be used with fiscal printers, providing the functionality of a cash register.

#### **EDUCACIÓN**

**UCV,** Caracas — *Electrical Engineer major in Electronics*JULY 2016